Finding Aid for Southeast Michigan Regional Ethnic Heritage Study Center records, 1970-1976
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Southeast Michigan Regional Ethnic Heritage Study Center records 1970-1976
Southeast Michigan Regional Ethnic Heritage Study Center.
3 linear feet
85414 Bd 2
Ethnic study program founded in part by Otto Feinstein of Wayne State University and concerned with making available and using ethnic materials in the classroom. Minutes, staff reports, and subject files; contain files relating to a survey in 1972 of ethnic radio programs, an ethnic survey of East Detroit School District residents in 1974, and materials relating to a teachers training program.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The records were acquired from the organization (donor no. 6793 ) in 1982.
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The record group is open to research.
The Southeast Michigan Regional Ethnic Heritage Study Center was formed in 1972 because of a growing interest in the history of ethnic groups, particularly those from Southern or Eastern Europe. The Center brought together a polyglot of interests which had coalesced around an ethnic study program loosely associated with the Monteith College of Wayne State University. Professor Otto Feinstein was instrumental in the founding of the Center and in its continuing operation. The organization's primary interest was in making available to and training educators in the use of materials regarding ethnicity prepared for classroom use. The Center, however, was funded primarily through special grants, and thus undertook a variety of projects reflecting the availability and interests of the funding source.
The records of the South East Michigan Regional Ethnic Heritage Study Center (1970-1976) are arranged alphabetically by subject or title. In addition to information about the body's goals and organization, found primarily in the minutes of the Board of Directors and the Executive Council as well as in the staff reports, there is detailed information about specific projects. Most interesting are a survey of ethnic radio programs (1972), an ethnic survey of East Detroit School District residents (1974) and manuscripts prepared for the TTT program (1972).
The records of the South East Michigan Regional Ethnic Heritage Study Center (1970-1976) measure three feet and are arranged alphabetically by subject or title. In addition to information about the body's goals and organization, found primarily in the minutes of the Board of Directors and the Executive Council as well as in the staff reports, there is detailed information about specific projects. Most interesting are a survey of ethnic radio programs (1972), an ethnic survey of East Detroit School District residents (1974) and manuscripts prepared for the TTT program (1972).
Subjects:
Eastpointe (Mich.); Education--Michigan.; Ethnology--Michigan.; Minorities--Michigan.; Radio broadcasting--Michigan.; Southeast Michigan Regional Ethnic Heritage Studies Center.
Contributors:
Feinstein, Otto, 1930- .
- Topical files
  - Bicentennial, ca. 1972 (Box 1)
  - Bleeke, Steve, Dramatic Presentations (Box 1)
  - Board of Directors
    - Membership Lists, 1973-1975 (Box 1)
    - Minutes and Mailings to Board Members, 1972-1975, 4 folders (Box 1)
  - Bylaws, 1972-1975 (Box 1)
  - Committees, 1971-1974 (Box 1)
  - Community Agencies Survey, ca. 1972 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1971-1976, 6 folders (Box 1)
  - Ethnic Conference, 1970-1972, 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Ethnic Directory, 1975 (Box 1)
  - Ethnic Heritage Advisory Council, 1975 (Box 1)
  - Ethnic Heritage Resource Centers, 1975 (Box 1)
  - Ethnic Heritage Studies Program, ca. 1975 (Box 1)
  - Ethnic Heritage Studies Program (TV Course), 1974 (Box 1)
  - Ethnic Multi-Media, Project (GA HUM 7610), 1976 (Box 2)
  - Ethnic Radio Survey, 1972 (Box 2)
  - Ethnic Studies Dissemination Project, 1975 (Box 2)
  - Ethnic Studies Training Project, 1975 (Box 2)
  - Ethnic Studies Workbooks, undated, 3 volumes (Box 2)
  - Ethnic Survey of East Detroit School District Residents, 1974 (Box 2)
  - Ethnic Tour of Windsor, ca. 1973 (Box 2)
  - "Ethnicity in Detroit," Slide/Tape Presentation, 1975 (Box 2)
  - Executive Council, 1973-1974 (Box 2)
  - Garlic, Clare, Handbook, 1974 (Box 2)
  - General Institutions Committee, 1974 (Box 2)
  - Health, Education and Welfare, U.S. Department of
    - Correspondence, 1974-1975, 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Reports, 1974-1977, 3 folders (Box 2)
    - Requests, 1974 (Box 2)
  - Meetings, 1973-1974 (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 3)
  - Multi-Ethnic Conference, Detroit Public Schools, 1974 (Box 3)
  - National Ethnic Studies Assembly (Box 3)
  - Press Releases, 1970-1975, 4 folders (Box 3)
  - Printed Matter (Box 3)
  - Proposals, undated (Box 3)
  - Rockefeller Grant Proposal, 1974-1975 (Box 3)
  - Staff
    - Meetings, 1974-1975, 2 folders (Box 3)
    - Reports, 1971-1976, 5 folders (Box 3)
    - Vitas (Box 3)
  - Training Program, 1974 (Box 3)
  - Tri-State Planning Conference, 1972 (Box 3)
  - TTT Program
    - Course Proposals, 1972 (Box 3)
    - Manuscripts, 1972 (Box 3)
    - Reports (Box 3)
  - Workshops, 1975 (Box 3)
  - Wrobel, Paul, Grant RF 701010, 1973-1975 (Box 3)